<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-21T16:15:47-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Voorwerpjes</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><author><name>Patrick Crumley</name></author><entry><title type="html">Hello, there</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/hello-there/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, there" /><published>2020-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/hello-there</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/hello-there/">&lt;p&gt;Hi. I’m Patrick. Right now I work as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.astro.princeton.edu/people/patrick-crumley&quot;&gt;computational astrophysicist&lt;/a&gt;, but I am
also in the middle of a career transition. I am starting a blog both as a way to
find ways to connect in this new normal, write down my thoughts, and document
things about my work in and outside of academia that I’m proud of or think might
help others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m choosing to call my blog &lt;em&gt;Voorwerpjes&lt;/em&gt;, which is a Dutch word that
translates into ‘little things’. But it is also the name of the class of the
astronomical object pictured below, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanny%27s_Voorwerp&quot;&gt;Hanny’s
Voorwerp&lt;/a&gt;. Voorwerpjes are
ionization echos of quasars, an anomalous astronomical object discovered by
citizen scientist in the Netherlands, Hanny van Arkel. She was volunteering as
part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zooniverse.org/projects/zookeeper/galaxy-zoo/&quot;&gt;Galaxy
Zoo&lt;/a&gt; project, when
she saw something new. She wanted to know what it was and it turned out to be a
whole class of objects no one had seen before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galaxy Zoo is a wonderful project that has lots volunteers who donate their to
categorize hundreds of thousands of galaxies based on their shape. It always
gives me a fuzzy feeling to think about—it combines the best parts of big data,
technology, and using the internet to build community and collaboration between
experts and non-experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to fill up this space with little things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hannys_voorwerp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanny's Voorwerp, credit to NASA&quot; /&gt;
Credit: NASA and the Galaxy Zoo Team&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Patrick Crumley</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Voorwerpjes" /><summary type="html">Hi. I’m Patrick. Right now I work as a computational astrophysicist, but I am also in the middle of a career transition. I am starting a blog both as a way to find ways to connect in this new normal, write down my thoughts, and document things about my work in and outside of academia that I’m proud of or think might help others.</summary></entry></feed>