<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-21T21:43:58-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Voorwerpjes</title><subtitle>Personal website of Patrick Crumley</subtitle><author><name>Patrick Crumley</name></author><entry><title type="html">Hello There.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/hello-there/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello There." /><published>2020-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/hello-there</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/hello-there/">&lt;p&gt;Hi. I’m Patrick. Right now I work as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.astro.princeton.edu/people/patrick-crumley&quot;&gt;computational
astrophysicist&lt;/a&gt;, but I
am also in the middle of a career transition. I am starting a blog to find ways
to connect in this new normal, write down my thoughts, and document things about
my work in and outside of academia that I’m proud of or think might help others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m choosing to call my blog &lt;em&gt;Voorwerpjes&lt;/em&gt;, which is a Dutch word that
translates into ‘little things’. But it is also the name of the class of the
astronomical object pictured below, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanny%27s_Voorwerp&quot;&gt;Hanny’s
Voorwerp&lt;/a&gt;. Voorwerpjes are
echoes of supermassive black holes, an anomalous astronomical object discovered by
a citizen scientist in the Netherlands, Hanny van Arkel. She was volunteering as
part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zooniverse.org/projects/zookeeper/galaxy-zoo/&quot;&gt;Galaxy
Zoo&lt;/a&gt; project when
she saw something new. It turned out to be a
whole class of objects no one had seen before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galaxy Zoo is a wonderful project that has lots volunteers who donate their time to
categorize hundreds of thousands of galaxies based on their shape. It always
gives me a fuzzy feeling to think about—the project combines the best parts of big
data and technology; using the internet to build community and collaboration between
experts and non-experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to fill up this space with little things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hannys_voorwerp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanny's Voorwerp, credit to NASA&quot; /&gt;
Credit: NASA and the Galaxy Zoo Team&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Patrick Crumley</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Voorwerpjes" /><summary type="html">Hi. I’m Patrick. Right now I work as a computational astrophysicist, but I am also in the middle of a career transition. I am starting a blog to find ways to connect in this new normal, write down my thoughts, and document things about my work in and outside of academia that I’m proud of or think might help others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Handy Resources for learning &amp;amp; doing ML</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/stats-ml-resources/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Handy Resources for learning &amp; doing ML" /><published>2020-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/stats-ml-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/stats-ml-resources/">&lt;p&gt;I attended the 2020 Spring session of Insight Data Science NYC, a 7 week long,
postdoctoral professional development fellowship from January through March.
I had a lot of fun doing it, but it was also surreal to watch the world shift
under our feet in early March during the outbreak of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is this theory in cosmology that the quantum field that permeates our
universe is only metastable. There exists a lower energy stable point than the
one we currently occupy. At some point, a place in the universe might
spontaneously tunnel from the “false vacuum” state into the “true vacuum.” The
part of the universe in the true vacuum state would then expand at the speed of
light, destroying everything it touched. It’s one of the ways our &lt;a href=&quot;https://cosmosmagazine.com/physics/vacuum-decay-ultimate-catastrophe/&quot;&gt;universe may
end&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March, it was&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Patrick Crumley</name></author><category term="Insight Data Science" /><category term="NYC" /><summary type="html">I attended the 2020 Spring session of Insight Data Science NYC, a 7 week long, postdoctoral professional development fellowship from January through March. I had a lot of fun doing it, but it was also surreal to watch the world shift under our feet in early March during the outbreak of COVID-19.</summary></entry></feed>